过滤器
Filters.
昭雪  第二季第五集
他拿到驾照了
He got it. He got his license.
我们本来打算回来再整理
We were gonna do this when we got back.
谢谢你  亲爱的
Thank you, honey.
你还在想什么  丹尼尔
What were you thinking, Daniel,
除了毁掉一个原本就很棒的厨房
besides destroying a perfectly good kitchen?
亲爱的  我知道现在一片狼藉...
Honey, I know it looks bad now --
抱歉  我理解错了
I'm sorry. I-I misunderstood.
你确实理解错了
Yeah. You did.
是我热情过度了
Got overly enthusiastic, I guess.
事已至此
Well, it's done now.
所以我们需要为将来制定个计划
So, we need a plan for going forward.
对  是要制定计划
Yes, a plan.
你有什么打算了吗
You got one?
我们还在想  泰德
We're working on it, Ted.
好吧
Okay.
但是现在我们可以先定几条规矩吗
For now, can we settle on a few rules?
当然可以  泰德  定规矩
Sure, Ted. Rules.
早上九点前下午六点后不许工作
No work before 9:00 a.m. or after 6:00,
不许搞破坏
no demolition
除非要更换的设备已经准备就绪
before replacement supplies are ready to install,
完事要随手打扫
and clean up as you go.
-不能影响家里人的正常生活  -当然
- We need to keep it functional for the family. - Of course.
但是首先
First things first.
你需要把这些损坏的胶合板换成新的
You need to replace some of this damaged plywood.
还用乙烯基胶合板吗
You gonna do vinyl again?
不  这点我确定  这个我来就行
No. That much I'm sure of. No, I got it.
没事
It's fine.
去曼斯维尔路上新开的那家木材店看看
Try that new lumber place out there on Masseyville Road.
我上班快迟到了  不然就跟你一起去
I'd go with you, but I'm already running late for work.
你开卡车去吧
Take the truck.
另一辆车钥匙给我好吗
You mind?
好的
No, of course not.
那祝你们好运
Well...Good luck.
没事  他就是大吃了一惊而已
He'll be all right. He's just surprised, is all.
是啊
Of course he is.
抱歉  我还以为...
I'm -- I'm sorry. I just thought it was...
我也不知道
I don't know.
不会有事的
It's gonna be great.
我觉得一切都很好
I'm very excited about everything.
你是个有风度的人  母亲
You're a good sport, mother.
我去换衣服
I'll go get changed.
还没走啊
Still here.
是啊  我在看你的书
Yeah, I was just, uh, checking out your book.
知道了
I see.
我回避  你换衣服吧
I'll, uh -- I'll step out so you can change.
没事  小泰
That's okay, Teddy.
"爱有时清晰可见有时若隐若现
"Love may be of the seen and of the unseen,
有时现世便有  有时确无此物
"of the present, of the absent.
因此  所爱之物
"Consequently, a thing to be loved
便不随信仰
"is not so adapted to faith,
犹如希冀之事
"as a thing to be hoped for,
因为希望总是渺茫虚无"
since hope is always of the absent and the unseen."
言语犀利啊
Pretty intense.
说实话  里面很多内容我都不懂
I don't understand a lot of it, truth be told.
有时我就随便读读
Sometimes, I just let it wash over me,
看看能记住什么
see what sticks.
我喜欢这样
I like that.
我喜欢你
I like you.
我也喜欢你  小泰
I like you, too, Teddy...
有时候吧
Sometimes.
要握手约定吗  朋友
Want to shake on it, friend?
你很聪颖  托妮
You're smart, Tawney.
我知道我以前没经常跟你说
I know I probably don't say it enough,
甚至从没说过
or maybe never.
真的很抱歉  最近我态度一直不好
I am really sorry for the way I've been acting.
今天又是新的一天嘛
Well, today's a new day.
人不能太生气  小泰
Can't get so angry, Teddy.
我知道
I know.
愤怒会吞噬你
It'll consume you.
我知道
I know.
然后会吞噬我们两个人
Then it'll consume us.
看到没  你真聪明
See? Smart.
希望今天你过得愉快  托妮
I hope it's a good day for you, Tawney.
你也是
You too.
你正常收银的灯没亮
Your light's not on.
是啊
Oh. Right.
谢谢
Thank you.
皮娜特生孩子怎么样了
How was Peanut's labor?
这个我还不清楚  我是新来的
I don't know about that. I'm new.
不好意思
Sorry.
有时候东西扫不出来
Dang thing gets stuck every once in a while,
我也听说过
from what I hear.
没事  阿曼莎
You are doing just fine... Amantha.
一共19.11美元
Your total is $19.11.
我不清楚皮娜特的孩子
Yeah, I don't know about Peanut's baby
还有她的情况  但是如果你想知道
or her labor or anything, but I can find out for you
-我可以帮你问问  女士  -谢谢你
- if you'd like, ma'am. - Oh, that's sweet of you.
你输密码了吗
Did you, um, enter the P.I.N.?
已经输了
P.I.N.'s in.
能再刷一遍卡吗
Will you swipe it again?
好像需要重新来一遍
I think I'm just gonna have to cancel it and start over.
还是先等等...
Or better yet...
薇恩
Wynn...
我现在有事找你  薇恩
I need you, like, right away, Wynn,
快点过来
like, right away.
很抱歉
Sorry, y'all.
我有点呆头呆脑
Register's acting loopy.
以后记得说  "二号收银台
Please say, "I need a manager
需要经理"  记得说"经理"
on check stand two, please, a manager."
但你是这里唯一的经理啊
But you're the only manager.
-请再刷一遍  珍妮  -好
- Swipe it again, please, Ginny. - Okay.
-剩下的付现金吗  -对
- You doing cash for the rest? - Yep.
她用的是电子福利转账
That's EBT she's using.
只能买食品
Food items only.
否则转账就会被拒绝
Otherwise, it'll reject the transaction.
电子福利转账
EBT?
食品救济券对吗
Oh, food stamps?
是补助
Assistance.
屏幕上显示了
And it's right there on the screen.
皮娜特怎么样了
How's Peanut?
我来告诉你独家新闻
Let me tell you the scoop --
她整整生了九个小时  没有硬膜外麻醉
Nine hours of labor, no epidural.
生了个男孩  叫怀亚特·安德鲁
Baby's a boy named Wyatt Andrew.
宝宝整整11磅5盎司重
Tips the scale at a solid 11 pounds, 5 ounces.
天哪
Good God!
不好意思  只是...
Sorry. It's just a --
一个大块头宝宝啊
A huge dang kid.
皮娜特要恢复可能需要一段时间了
Might be a while before Peanut's back on her feet.
谢谢
Thank you.
祝您愉快
You have a nice day.
下一位
Who's next?
拜拜
Bye.
轮辋租赁区
这个角落最合适了
This felt like the best corner.
从路上可以看到这里
You know, you can see it from the road,
但是又不会遮挡什么
but it's not blocking anything.
过往的人应该都能吸引过来
I figured we'd get the drive-bys and the looky-loos.
我们讨论的时候我态度很明确
I was clear when we discussed this,
我没有授权你使用公司资金
I did not authorize you to use company funds.
我用的不是公司资金  爸  是我自己的钱
It's not company funds, Dad. It's my funds.
你哪里弄的这么多钱买这些
Where did you get the money to pay for all this?
银行贷款
Got a bank loan.
贷款
A loan?
用什么担保的
Secured with what?
这个你不用管  爸爸
It's not your concern, Dad.
你用你们家房子抵押了
You put up your house.
对
Yep.
儿子啊
Oh, son.
不会有事的  爸爸
It's gonna be okay, Dad.
我非常确定  改变是在所难免的
I feel it in my bones. Change is inevitable.
得走在时代前列啊
You got to get out in front of it.
印第安泉商店
来看还是来买
You a browser or a buyer?
都可以
One of them.
你决定要买东西了
Well, let me know if you decide
记得告诉我
to cross over the threshold into consumerism.
其实我在找一件东西
Actually, I am looking for something specifically.
我喜欢这个
Well, I like that...
有时候吧
Sometimes.
一个韦奇伍德炉子
A Wedgewood Stove.
要几个炉膛的
How many burners?
四个
Four.
单个烤炉还有烤箱
Single broiler? Oven?
是的
Yes.
下面是要带保温储物箱的还是全是烤箱的
Storage compartment/warmer or all oven below?
都可以
Either, I suppose.
宽度呢
How wide?
36到40英寸
36 to 40 inches.
我猜你想要好用的吧
Good working condition, I'd imagine.
当然  那样最好了
It's preferable, yes.
要白色  黑色还是蓝色的
White, black, blue?
黑色
Black.
没有  根本没有韦奇伍德牌子的东西
Nope. Don't have a Wedgewood.
你这里卖炉子吗
Do you have any stoves at all?
不卖
Not really.
曾经有过一大堆老古董
Used to keep a mess of them old-timey things.
不舍得送人
Couldn't give 'em away.
现在都留不住了
Now you can't keep 'em.
都是"南方新贵族"闹的
The New South Bourgeoisie.
你是其中一员吗
You part of that group?
我觉得我不够资格加入
I don't think I qualify.
他们攒够了那些小钱
Eh, they got enough of that trickle-down money
就想花钱买点文化气息或品味
makes 'em want to buy some culture or class or...
或许只是淘淘旧货
or maybe they're just fish.
我也不了解  我只是尽可能的帮忙而已
Hell, I don't know. I just try to oblige when I can.
所以有些小钱就归你了
So some of that money trickles down to you.
为什么不要呢
Well, why the hell not?
我的爱国程度不亚于他们
I'm as much of a patriot as they are.
我只是喜欢老式炉子而已
I just like old stoves.
多谢你的介绍
Well, uh, thank you for your time.
你住在附近吗
You, uh, live around here?
是的
I do, yes.
我会帮你四处问问
I'll send your request out to the universe
仔细打听打听的
and lay my ear to the cosmic rails, as it were,
看看有没有回应
wait for a reply.
谢谢你
I'd appreciate that.
你觉得我在敷衍你吧
You think I'm bullshitting, don't you?
正相反
On the contrary.
这是我的电话号  过两天给我打电话
Here's my number. Give me a call in a few days.
我会告诉你有没有线索的
And I'll let you know if I got a lead.
谢谢  我会打给你的
Thank you. I will.
经常出门吗
Get out much?
什么
I'm sorry?
比如晚上有什么社交活动吗
You socialize, like, at night?
-天黑之后  -理论上...
- After dark? - In theory...
理论上  我今晚要办个派对
Well, in theory, I'm having a party tonight.
地址在名片上
My address is on the card.
要是你抗拒不了
So, if you're intrigued
狂野  奇异  精彩的东西...
by the wild, weird, and wonderful --
我承认  精不精彩不好说
Okay, can't guarantee the "Wonderful."
但其他的...
But the others...
老天爷啊
oh, good lord god.
总之  我很欢迎你来
Anyway, you'd be more than welcome.
为什么要邀请我去你家
Why would you invite me to your home?
想听实话吗
You want me to be honest?
是的
I would, yes.
你差不多是我见过的最孤独的人了
You're about the loneliest person I've ever seen.
孩子  要是你来我的派对
And if you come to one of my parties, son,
你可能仍感孤独  但你不会是孤身一人
you may still be lonely, but you will not be alone.
或者喝个烂醉  看你怎么选了
Or sober, if you so choose.
我叫莱斯利  名里有个Z
Name's Lezley, with a "Z."
我叫丹尼尔
Daniel.
D开头
With a "D."
D开头的丹尼尔
Okay, Daniel with a "D."
要是我今晚没见到你
If I don't see you tonight
或是你不想来和我们一起疯的话
and you don't feel like joining the fray,
那就过两天给我打电话问炉子的事吧
then you give me a call in a few on the stove, hear?
没问题
Will do.
恕我直言  地方检察官夫人
All due respect, Madam district attorney,
你喝酒了吗
Have you been drinking?
因为我难以想象一个神志清醒的人
'Cause I can't imagine a sober person
会去考虑给丹尼尔·霍顿一个认罪协议
even considering offering Daniel Holden a plea deal.
我说过了  议员  什么都没给呢
And, as I said, nothing's been offered yet, Senator.
但我希望你知道我很看重你的意见
But I did want you to know that I value your opinion.
我的意见是
Well, my opinion is,
你忘了这个案子中的事实
you've forgotten the facts of this case.
我连这个案子的细节都没忘
I've not forgotten the details of this case,
如果你是这个意思的话
if that's what you meant.
如果我明天把这个案子送上法庭
I'm no longer confident that if I take this case
我没有信心能找到12个
to trial tomorrow I'd be able to find 12 people
愿意把那个男人送回死囚牢房的陪审员
who'd be willing to put that man back on death row.
所以你就让他认罪然后结案
So, you'd let him plea out of it...
因为你担心审判中你的公诉能力不足
because you're afraid of your prosecutorial abilities in a trial?
不  我看重的是证据
No, I'm looking at the evidence --
精液不能将他和受害人直接联系起来
no sperm clearly tying him to the victim.
我们清楚他会宣称遭到逼供
We know he's gonna claim forced confession.
要是那份认罪书被否决了怎么办
What if that confession gets thrown out?
不会被否决的
It won't get thrown out.
要是被否决了怎么办
What if that confession gets thrown out?
我们只剩两个关键证人的证词了
We are down to the testimony of our two key witnesses.
特雷·威利斯仍坚持原始证词
Trey Willis stands by his original testimony.
这点对我们有利
That's in our favor.
乔治·梅尔顿已经不知所踪了
George Melton has dropped off the radar.
认罪免死刑
Plea deal for time served.
加刑十年
Plus 10.
加十年他又会什么时候出狱
10 means he's out in what?
六年后  八年后
Six? Eight?
这一步足以毁了我们的事业啊
That's the kind of move that can kill a career.
那你给我想个方法  罗兰  救救我们俩
Give me another option, Roland, one that saves both of us.
我听着呢
I'm open.
好了  "胡诌"
Okay. "Codswallop."
胡诌
Codswallop.
通常被简称为鳕鱼的鱼
A fish commonly abbreviated to "Cod."
错了  你只剩87分了
Wrong. And you're down to 87 points.
-是"胡说八道"的意思  -胡说八道
- It means "Nonsense". - Nonsense?
比如"奈尔正在喋喋不休地胡诌个没完"
As in, "Niles is incessantly jabbering codswallop."
-奈尔  -奈尔
- Niles? - Niles.
喋喋不休个没完
Incessantly jabbering.
你差点就能用那个短语赢回一分了  妈
You almost get a point back for that one, mother.
我已经92分了
Hey. I'm at 92.
他已经减到87了  你想刮地板还是读词
And he's down to 87. You want to scrape or read?
把书给我
Give me that.
选好了  "前台"
All right. Uh, "Proscenium."
-剧院里的舞台前缘  -舞台口
- That's the arch in the theater. - Apron of the stage.
老弟  你得挑个难点的词
You got to pick harder words, brother.
阿曼莎
Amantha.
这真是...
Wow. This is really, uh...
要来帮帮我们吗
You want to help, honey?
不了  我只是来洗个衣服
Oh, no. I just stopped by to do laundry.
没零钱去洗衣店了
Ran out of quarters.
可以吗
Is that okay?
当然了
Of course.
等不及要看看能修成什么样了
Can't wait to see how it turns out.
后现代主义风格
It's, uh, postmodern.
解构主义
Deconstructionist.
没有会更好
It speaks with its absence.
你们看报纸了吗
Y'all see in the paper?
盖恩斯死了
Gaines died.
你知道卢瑟福·盖恩斯是谁吧  杰瑞德
You know who, uh, Rutherford Gaines was, Jared?
他不是你的律师吗
Wasn't he your lawyer?
年轻人知道不少不该知道的事啊
Young man knows more than he lets on.
你还认识谁  杰瑞德
What else do you know, Jared?
我也不清楚
I don't know.
你不清楚你还认识谁
You don't know what else you know?
是啊
No.
看来这病是遗传的啊
It's a family disease.
盖恩斯是怎么死的
How did Gaines die?
内疚而死或是癌症吧  我忘了
Regret or cancer. I forget.
他活得可真够久的  不是吗
He lived a long life, didn't he?
希望我们也能长命百岁
May we all.
我去拿点砂纸
I'm gonna go get some sandpaper.
借过一下
Excuse me.
借过
这厨房是什么时候被毁的
So, when did the wrecking ball hit the kitchen?
你就不担心没人知道你在做什么吗
You at all worried that none of you know what you're doing?
有点吧
Probably.
你看起来很疲倦啊  宝贝
You look tired, sweetheart.
一直在打包行李吗
You been packing up your place?
没有  妈  我找了个工作
No, mother. I got a job.
是吗  在亚特兰大吗
Really? In Atlanta?
不  在波利
No, in Paulie.
什么
What?
平价商店
Thrifty Town.
-别闹  到底在哪  -他们几乎从不招人
- Seriously, where? - They hardly ever hire.
但幸运的是
But as luck would have it,
我在正确的时间出现在了正确的地方
I walked in at just the right time.
皮娜特休产假去了
Peanut went out on maternity leave.
我有点没搞懂  阿曼莎
I'm afraid I don't entirely understand, Amantha.
你在给一个叫皮娜特的人打工吗
You are working for someone named Peanut?
不  因为皮娜特我才有了工作
No, mother. I am working because of Peanut.
她正在坐月子
She's recovering.
为什么
Why, honey?
按我的理解
As I understand it,
生完孩子得恢复一段时间
you need some time after you deliver a child,
特别是生了一个11磅重的大胖孩之后
especially an 11-pounder like Wyatt Andrew.
我是问你为什么要在平价商店找工作
No, I mean why did you take a job at Thrifty Town?
让我想想  因为我需要钱
Oh, well, let's see. I need money.
我想就是这个原因  你还有去污剂吗
I think that's about it. You have any stain stick?
我有预洁剂
I have pre-wash.
那个就行
That should do it.
谢谢
Thanks.
难以置信我们以前用这里停车
Hard to believe we used to park cars in here.
是啊  我们没丢掉的东西就是真实的自己
Yes, we are what we don't throw away.
泰迪熊和杠铃
Teddy bears and barbells,
你骑过的自行车
your old bike.
坦克牌自行车
The tank.
你曾骑着它到处逛
You rode that thing everywhere.
大家都说我疯了
People thought I was crazy,
我明明能开辆好车的
riding a bike to the grocery store
却骑着自行车去杂货店
when I could drive a perfectly good car.
共产主义
Communist.
是你爸爸把这些篮子装上的
Your daddy put these baskets on.
无意冒犯  可每次你骑在这车上时
No offense, but you always reminded me
都让我想起了坏女巫
of the wicked witch when you rode this.
这怎么能算是冒犯呢
How could I possibly be offended?
你为什么不骑了呢
Why did you stop riding it?
我觉得我们没必要讲这些伤心事
I don't think we need to tell sad stories.
人生苦短
Life's too short.
正因如此  我们才要说出来
That's is why we have to tell.
跟我有关  对吗
It's about me, isn't it?
亲爱的  我不想提起这些
Honey, I don't want to tell this.
求你了  妈妈
Please, mama,
我自己无法填补这些空白
I can't fill in the gaps on my own.
我需要听你讲
I need to hear.
那是1995年
It was in 1995,
7月10号
July the 10th.
我买了件新连衣裙
I'd bought a new dress to wear...
黄色花朵图案  那种夏季野餐经常穿的
yellow flowers, like a summer picnic dress.
那天商店快关门了我才买那件衣服的
I-I grabbed it right before the store closed that day.
我不知道为什么买那件衣服
I have no idea why I bought that dress.
那不是我一贯风格
It was perverse.
等离开商店的时候  我就是
And when the time came to go, I just...
我就是做不到
I-I just couldn't do it.
盖恩斯先生说这是个形式
Mr. Gaines said it was a formality,
处决还会继续执行
that the execution would be stayed again,
可是
but...
我只是一个劲儿地上下楼
Anyway, I just kept walking up and down the stairs,
不停看表
checking the clock.
最后  我来到这里看见了我的自行车
Finally, I-I came out here. I saw my bike.
你爸爸听到车库门开了
Your dad heard the garage open
他出来问我在干什么
and came out and asked me what was I doing.
我说  我要骑车兜兜风
I said, "I'm... I'm gonna take a ride."
-你别去  -不  我要去
- "No, you're not." - "Yes, I am."
珍妮特  别逼我开车在后面跟着你
"Janet, don't make me get in the car and follow you."
我说  就让我去吧
I said, "Let me be."
他同意了
And he did.
我骑着车越过整条街  穿过小镇
Rode down the street... and I rode through town,
骑过水塔  骑过卫星站
past the water tower, past the satellites,
就穿着那件可笑的黄裙子
in that ridiculous yellow dress.
我也不知道骑了多久
I rode for I don't know how long,
直到后半夜了我才停下
until I-I thought midnight had passed.
直到停下来了  我才意识到我压到一个钉子
When I stopped, I realized that I'd run over a nail
后轮胎都瘪了
and the back tire was flat.
我转身往回
I turned around,
就那样瘪着轮胎一直骑回了家
rode it the whole way home that way.
我清楚地记得当你爸爸告诉我
I remember exactly where I was standing
他们再次延期处决你时我站在哪儿
when your dad told me that they'd given you
我就站在家门前
another stay... right by the front door,
那个雕着天鹅图案的旧黄铜伞架旁边
by that old brass umbrella stand with the swan on it.
我记得是他安抚我入睡
I remember he helped me to bed.
我扔了那条裙子
I threw out that dress.
我想我要去给自己做个三明治
I, uh, think I'm gonna go make myself a sandwich.
你要吃一个吗
Would you like one?
不了  谢谢
No, thank you.
你是哪位
Who are you?
我也不知道
I'm not sure.
你看起来似曾相识
You look familiar.
如果你想起来了  能告诉我吗
If you figure it out, will you let me know?
老天  我真高兴你来了
God, I'm glad you're here.
有点儿出乎我妈妈的意料
Kind of blew mom's mind.
是因为你找的那份工作吗
Was that the point of getting a job at...
是在哪儿来着
where, again?
平价商店  乔恩
Thrifty Town, Jon.
我现在在平价商店打工
I am working at Thrifty Town
因为毫不夸张地说我没钱搬去亚特兰大
because I literally cannot afford to move to Atlanta,
而梅尔文是绝不会退给我
and Melvin is unyielding on any refunds
最后一个月的房租和押金的
of last month's rent and deposit.
他想永远把你栓在这里
Well, he wants to keep you here forever.
他人很好
He's sweet.
他是我的情敌
He's my competition.
事实上  生活中
Actually, the idea of having
出现些别的事是一种解脱
something to show up for is a relief,
想想其他的事而不是只关注
to think of something other than...
你自己
yourself?
我真不敢相信你竟然这么说
I cannot believe you just said that.
不过也许你说的对
But maybe.
说到工作
Speaking of jobs...
威廉给我打了个很有意思的电话
I got an interesting call from William.
司法部门的威廉吗
William from Justice row?
他在机场给我打的电话
He called me at the airport.
他说彼得·穆伦要走了
He said Peter Mullen's leaving
他们要找人接替他的位置
and they need a replacement.
他们是让你去吗
And they're asking you?
他们要我去
They're asking me.
你有多长时间考虑这件事
How long do you have to think about it?
他让我在去瓦尔纳的路上给他打电话
He wants me to call him on my way to Varner
周三还要去艾迪威尔监狱  周五是河湾监狱
before Eddyville on Wednesday and Riverbend on Friday.
死囚牢之旅吗
Death row tour?
我们要印纪念T裇吗
Should we print T-shirts?
我需要些改变  你明白吗
I just need a change, you know?
你会考虑去波士顿吗
Would you consider Boston?
我必须现在回答你吗
Do I have to answer right now?
好好考虑下
Think about it?
我会的
Okay.
但是首先
But first,
我们有一些事
we have some stuff
真的需要谈谈了
that we really need to talk about.
-一些事  -是啊
- Stuff? - Yeah.
超级秘密的事  而且
It's super-secret, and...
我甚至不确定
I'm not really sure
是否应该在这儿说
we should even be out here talking about it,
因为谁知道会不会有人在偷听
because we don't know who might be listening in.
通风孔有可能安装了窃听麦克风
May have hidden microphones in the vents.
麦克风
Microphones.
那你觉得
Do you think it...
那你觉得如果在卧室谈会不会更安全些
do you think it would be better in the bedroom?
也许
Maybe.
我们应该检查检查
We should probably check.
我查这边  你去查那边
I'll go that way. You go that way.
今天把要展示的商品都布置好了
Got the display all set up today.
午饭后还有几个人来店里了
Even had a couple folks pop in after lunch
来参观了一下
to take a look around.
现在只是时间的问题了  我就知道
Only a matter of time now, I know it.
真是太好了
That's great.
确实如此  对吗
It is, right?
真的很好
Yeah, it really is.
你怎么紧锁着眉头啊
You got the worried eyebrows.
没什么
It's nothing.
这就意味着有问题
Which means it's something.
只是因为
Well, it's just...
我想去上学
I want to go to school.
上学
School.
我知道有点儿突然
I know it's kind of out of the blue.
-我只是  -什么学校
- I just... - What kind of school?
大学
College.
我想修一些课程
I want to take classes...
应该是夜校课程
night classes, I guess.
我还是想拿到文凭
Want to get my degree, eventually.
好啊
Okay.
你已经考虑很久了吧
So, you've been thinking about this for a while.
是有一段日子了
A little while, yeah.
之前怎么只字未提呢
How come you haven't said anything?
我不知道
I don't know.
小泰  我想
Teddy, I guess...
我的经期晚了
my period's late.
你今天晚上真是让我各种惊喜啊
Well, you're just full of surprises tonight.
我不是刻意如此
I'm not trying to be.
你的经期之前也晚过
You've been late before.
我知道
I know.
但这次感觉不一样
This feels different.
怎么个不一样
Different how?
我不知道  我想是感觉更真实吧
I don't know. More... real, I guess.
明白
Okay.
那么
Well...
我是不是应该去药店买那种试纸试试
Should I go get one of those tests from the drug store?
应该测测吧
I guess we should.
好吧  现在就去买吗
Okay. Should I go right now?
等明天再去吧
We can wait till tomorrow.
只有我们俩吗
Just us chickens?
只有我们俩
Just us chickens.
今天早上你处理得不是很好
You didn't handle that well this morning.
他是个成年人了  珍妮特
He's a grown man, Janet.
但他受过伤害  泰德
He's a damaged one, Ted.
我知道  那他也不能肆意妄为
I know that, but he can't just do things
然后一点责任也不负吧
and not face some responsibility for it.
我觉得他为别人的错事
It seems to me that he's had
负的责任已经够多了
more than his fair share of being held responsible.
我知道
I realize that.
你不知道这事对他的伤害有多大
You don't know how hard this is on him.
大家都不好受  包括我
It's tough on everyone, even me.
那你跟我说说你怎么不好受了
Why don't you tell me all about how you've suffered?
-你没懂我的意思  -不  是你没懂
- You're not listening. - No, you're not listening.
不许你再像今天早上那样
You won't ever speak to him again the way
跟他说话
you spoke to him this morning.
-我不允许  -你不允许
- I won't allow it. - You won't allow it?
这里是他的家  不能那样对待他
He won't be treated like that in his own home.
这里也是我的家啊
Which is my home, too.
但他比你来的早
It was his first.
我去睡了
I'm going to bed.
最多是被误导了
He was misguided, the best.
我觉得你说的不对  兰诺
I think you're wrong, Lionel.
我觉得他们是想做好事
I think what they were trying to do is positive, man.
从一开始就明显行不通
It was doomed from the start.
用哪个白痴的卡迪拉克都比这强
Occupy some dickhead's Cadillac would have worked better.
就像唐纳德的理想黄金国
Yeah, like the Donalds' Eldorado.
他来了  过来坐吧
And this one! Chime in.
占领运动  明确失败之处
Occupy movement. Pinpoint its failure.
占领什么
Occupy what?
点就在这儿
Exactly.
我只知道革命从来都不是
All I know is revolution ain't never been fomented
那些只能住帐篷的可怜人发起的
by poor people sitting on their ass in tents.
俄国革命就是农民起义来的
The Russian revolution was started by peasants.
农民
Peasants, huh?
虽然我不知道他们住的是不是帐篷
I don't know if they lived in tents, though.
"托尔斯泰大师"说起俄国革命
Tolstoy here talking about
就好像他亲身经历过一样
the Russian revolution like he was there.
你会想喝点的  朋友
You're gonna need this, friend.
我们见过吗
I know you?
应该没有
I don't think so.
你确定吗
You sure?
别管他了  兰诺
Leave him alone, Lionel.
他看起来好眼熟
Dude looks familiar.
派对愉快
Enjoy your night.
名字拼写中有D的丹尼尔来了
Yeah, that's my buddy Daniel with a "D"!
帮我个忙  抓住那头
Give me a hand with this thing. Grab the end of it.
抓紧
Grab it.
这是一个老人在安斯利公园给我的
I got it from an old queen in Ansley Park,
怎么劝都劝不住
and it was not easy to talk him out of.
进来
Right in there.
就放那  谢谢
Set it down right there. Thank you.
绑马尾辫的怪人欺负你啦
Little squirrely one with a rattail giving you shit?
没关系的
It's okay.
哥们儿  拜托
Oh, brother, please.
兰诺比你早到两个小时
Lionel gets here two hours early
就是为了占那把旧椅子
just to claim a spot on that old chair.
他也没什么特别的
He ain't got nothing else,
除了有个两英寸的小弟弟
except a two-inch pee-pee.
我去弄杯喝的
Let me get us a shot of something.
等等
Hey, hey, now.
站住  "逃亡列车"  你要去哪
Hold on, now, runaway train. Where you headed?
回家  我
Home. I --
那可不行  怎么能这么早就走
Not allowed. Not yet.
你不是无缘无故就来了吧
You came here for a reason.
总不能空手而归
You best ride that out.
如果我根本不知道是什么缘故呢
What if I don't know the reason?
总会有缘由  但需要你去发现
Well, reason's known, yet also for you to discover.
我也不知道这句话什么意思
I don't know what that means.
给你  把这个系在皮带上
But here, hook this around your belt loop.
接下来的一小时
For the next hour,
我们要拴在一条绳上
you and me gonna stay tethered,
形影不离
remain in a radius of each other,
就像围绕恒星运转的行星一样
like orbiting planets.
还是算了
I-I don't think so.
你在怕什么呢
What are you afraid of?
我只是不喜欢
I'd just prefer not to be...
被绑住
tied to anything.
有道理
You may have a point there.
那就弄个隐形轨道半径吧
Okay, we'll, uh, make the radius implied.
-隐形的  -没错
- Implied? - Yes.
隐形半径  不用绳子了
Implied radius. No cord.
就一小时  我把厨房的闹钟定好
One hour. I'll just set the kitchen timer.
这一小时里
For that hour...
这是来自伟大的
here is your great mandate
懂的事很多的
from the mouth of the great Lezley,
莱斯利的命令
who knows not a hell of a lot --
假装一下
act as if.
假装什么
As if what?
假装属于这里  丹尼尔  跟我们一样
As if you belong here, Daniel, with us,
跟其他乘客一样
your fellow travelers.
来吧  哥们儿  你来都来了
Come on, buddy. You come this far.
我想我可以喝几杯啤酒
I suppose I could have a beer.
大喊几声
Do some yelling.
起立
Stand up.
绑在他身上
Wrap this around him.
什么
What?
照做就是了  辛迪
Just do it, Cindy.
我觉得这样不...
No, I don't think that this is a --
很明显  隐形绳子没有用
Clearly, the implied radius was not sufficient.
我一眼没看住它就没用了
Crept off when I weren't looking.
辛迪  能不能请你
Cindy, would you be so kind
-给我们倒杯酒  -自己倒  莱斯利
- as to get us a refill? - Get your own, Lezley.
我们现在有重要的事
We're kind of in the middle of something important here.
你真奇怪
You're weird.
哥们儿  你没有好好装哦
Buddy, you ain't acting as if.
是啊
Uh, yeah.
没有想象的那么简单吧
It's harder than it looks, ain't it?
确实
Exceedingly.
如果你整天都自己一个人坐着
How you ever gonna get where you need to go
又怎么能找到属于自己的地方呢
sitting off by yourself all the time?
你怎么知道我需要离开呢
What makes you think I want to go anywhere?
你难道还没逃避够吗
Ain't you done enough of that in your life?
逃避的结果又如何呢
Where did that get you?
结果是来了这里
Well, unfortunately, here.
你读过《流浪者之歌》吗
You ever read "Siddhartha"?
闲的时候读过
In my spare time.
他就是从逃避世界中开悟的吗
He reach enlightenment by being apart from the world?
不是
Um, no.
没错  他不是
That is correct. He did not.
他让你去接触世界
He proffered you got to be in the world.
去体验探索
Got to get dirty,
交际一下什么的
rub elbows and shit.
所有读新闻的都知道
Look, any man reads a newspaper knows
丹尼尔·霍顿一度放肆
Daniel with a "D" Holden's overdue a little excess,
恣意妄为
a little indulgence of the senses.
在午夜微光下
Some late-night, low-light
纠结缠绵
intermingling and intertangling.
我希望你指的是跟女人
I hope you're suggesting girls.
这派对上的一半女孩都想和你睡
Half of which at this party want to sleep with you.
另一半只是有点怕你
The other half are afraid of you,
但这一半的一半依旧想和你睡
and half of them still want to sleep with you.
这和运气没关系
It ain't even about luck at this point.
你就是这样开悟的吗
And that's how you reach enlightenment?
谁在乎啊  拜托  哥们儿
Who gives a shit? Come on, buddy.
该回到人类生活中来了
It's time to join the human race,
不管以何种方式
in all its permutations.
起锚啦  小丹尼
Anchors aweigh, Danny boy.
待会儿用的
For later on.
死神蘑菇吗
Are they shrooms?
死神蘑菇的起源
Back to the source.
你到底想干嘛  莱斯利
What's your game, Lezley?
你已经知道该怎么做了  丹尼尔
You already know what to do, Daniel.
千万别忘了
Just got to remember it.
接受一切吧  丹尼尔
Take in everything, Daniel.
接受一切
Everything.
扔吧
Pull.
下一个是什么
What's next?
爵士乐
Spin doctors.
棒
Great!
扔吧
Pull.
该你了  哥们儿
Your turn, buddy.
不了
No.
你得装的像样点  孩子
You got to act as if, son.
假装我会用枪吗
As if I know how to shoot a gun?
危险就是乐趣
The danger's what makes it fun.
来吧  丹
Come on, Dan.
帮个忙
Do the world a favor.
把迈克尔·波顿炸上天吧[该专辑歌手]
Blow old Michael Bolton off to bloody hell, won't you?
丹尼尔
Daniel!
丹尼尔  丹尼尔  丹尼尔
Daniel! Daniel! Daniel!
Daniel! Daniel! Buddy?
你还好吗
You here?
好了
Yeah.
扔吧
Pull!